So one day you get this email from a delivery service,
saying that they're stuck with your package.
Annoying,
right?
Thankfully,
the problem is easy to fix this time.
All you have to do is click on a link to confirm your address.
You do as you're told and
Whoops,
you just became a victim of a phishing scam.
Everyone can get scammed this way.
There's no shame in that.
However,
with just some basic knowledge,
you can avoid the trap.
Here's phishing attacks,
explained in 2 minutes.
So,
what is a phishing attack?
Strictly speaking,
it's an attempt to deceive you by various means of communication.
Such attacks are conducted through emails,
text messages,
social media,
phone calls,
and pretty much any other way.
Their goal is to get your data,
such as a password,
an ID number,
or a bank account login.
Or to plant malware on your computer,
which usually does the same thing,
steals your data on top of making the computer unusable.
The attackers usually use one of two tactics.
They either bank on urgency
or try to gain your trust
by impersonating somebody,
or both.
So,
they might send you a fake document,
such as an invoice
or an offer to upgrade your account,
or even pretend to be a relative or a friend.
Then you either click on a link and download a malicious file,
or proceed to a fake version of a website they created,
and straight up give them what they want.
And avoiding such attacks is no easy task.
You have to be very vigilant.
Always check the source,
be it an email,
a phone number,
or a website.
Is it real?
Does it look suspicious?
Can you confirm it?
There are lots of other tips on how to avoid fishing,
so check out our other longer video where we
break down all the ways to avoid phishing attacks.
Thanks for watching.